{
    "id": "f72a959ff9ae49219d677bb1b63144de",
    "title": "Leave, Take Or Make",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "869408c2f0f740dfadcf8ca7162b4b04",
            "title": "Leave, Take Or Make",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "The company ……………………. shirts and trousers.",
                    "description": "We use the word make to talk about producing something. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "makes",
                        "takes",
                        "leaves"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Don’t ……………………… trouble.",
                    "description": "To make trouble is to cause trouble.",
                    "answers": [
                        "take",
                        "make",
                        "leave"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The circus …………………………. town this morning.",
                    "description": "To leave town is to go away from the town.",
                    "answers": [
                        "took",
                        "made",
                        "left"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The cigarette ……………………………. a bad taste in my mouth.",
                    "description": "To leave a bad taste is to cause a bad taste.",
                    "answers": [
                        "left",
                        "made",
                        "took"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Hurry or you won’t …………………….. the train.",
                    "description": "To make the train is to arrive in time for the train. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "leave",
                        "take",
                        "make"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The man ………………………….. most of his money to charity.",
                    "description": "Leave means bequeath here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "took",
                        "made",
                        "left"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He ……………………….. a wife and three grown sons.",
                    "description": "Here leave means be survived by.",
                    "answers": [
                        "took",
                        "made",
                        "left"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The military …………………….. control of the government.",
                    "description": "To take control is to seize control.",
                    "answers": [
                        "took",
                        "made",
                        "left"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "When buying a coat, look closely at its ……………………….",
                    "description": "Make can mean brand.",
                    "answers": [
                        "take",
                        "make"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………….. the rope in your right hand and pull.",
                    "description": "Take means grab here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Take",
                        "Make",
                        "Leave"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We have to ………………………. Rome by sunset.",
                    "description": "Make means reach or arrive at here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "make",
                        "take"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Becoming a doctor ……………………….. years of study.",
                    "description": "Here take means requires or demands.",
                    "answers": [
                        "makes",
                        "leaves",
                        "takes"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}